I wish I wasn't young and ???
This stair I'll sit and calm my fear
And tear everything all down 'round me
It's a good day to move on in ????
do the swaying trees hold
soyogu mori wa
memories of the gentle wind
kaze no kioku desu ka
what was held inside the
wareta kajitsu ga
fruit as it split at the skin
hakonda mono wa
I do wonder what
tabibito wa
the traveler will find in their journeys?
nani wo mitsukeru no deshou
will the stars grant them what they wish
hoshi ha sono yume wo
for while the sun is out
mitashimasuka
oh please tell me
oshiete
the reasons if
doushite
there's an end to all of this after what we see
moshimo owari ga aru no nara
your answers will
kotaete
work just fine with me
sore de ii
if we can be together now still
hitotsu ni nareru nara
I've wandered from place to place seeking something with no form
katachi nai nani ka wo motomenagara
aimlessly I walked, as I braved through every storm
kyou made samayoi tsudzukemashita
in this ever-changing volatile world we live in
meguri utsurou kono sekai no naka de
there are some things that will never change through thick and thin
kawaranai mono ga arimashita
my grateful words
arigatou
can be heard filling through the emptiness
genya ni hibiki watatta
of these lands before me
kodama no you ni
I'll say "Thank you"
arigatou
countless times to you
nando demo
as many as the stars that are shown
mizu no kagami ni utsuru
in this mirror of a lake now tonight
hikari no wa no you ni ima