Heave-ho!
Okay, just a couple more left.
Yeah. Let's close up shop
and go back to the Inside already.
It's a long trip back.
Right.
Wrong...
But it's very clean.
Almost as if...
Hey, did you guys hear that?
Hear what? We didn't hear anything.
There's someone here.
It might be a survivor.
Please hold on!
What if it's an Outsider?
What if it's an Insider that got cursed?
If we leave them, they may infect others!
We mustn't let a single one live!
If we don't prevent it from spreading,
what's the point?!
I'm responsible for this unit, so I'll take a look.
I knew I heard someone.
Hey, is someone there?!
We know you're there!
Do not run away. I'm from the military.
Don't worry. You're in good hands now!
Are you quite all right?
Yeah.
I'm okay.
My apologies. I understand it's easy to lose your footing
in the dark, but worry not. Dawn is upon us.
Did you hurt your leg?
Yeah, but I'm okay.
I see. Take as long as you need.
About that lantern...
You should've brought it.
Yes, I agree.
You must be bird-brained!
Indeed. What is your name?
Shiva.
Shiva, is it?
Why were you sleeping out in the wild?
Hmm, I don't know.
I thought I was sleeping at home with auntie...
I see.
I guess I'm bird-brained, too!
Wait...
You have horns!
Indeed.
And a tail!
I am an Outsider.
Does that mean you curse people?
I, myself, do not.
I can only speak for myself, however.
Really?
What's your name?
I have long since forgotten my name.
So I do not possess one.
Really?
Are we almost there?
Mhm?
To your home.
Yes. We should be able to see it soon.
So let's go!
Before we do...
I cannot touch you,
no matter how much your leg hurts,
but you can hold onto this.
Is something the matter?
Nah. It's just a funny way to use it.
Right you are.
Wrap it up with this after.
Like this?
Yes. Try not to wrap it too tight.
Shiva, aren't you afraid of me?
Mhm?
Why would I be?
Because of my appearance.
Does the way I look not faze you?
You don't look like me, but...
I don't know. Are you scared of me?
No, I am not.
Same as me, then.
Do you live alone?
Yes.
It's more that I drop by here on occasion.
Really?
Do you know where your house is?
No, I dunno.
Okay.
Your injury isn't too serious,
but if you'd like, you may rest here
until you're well again.
There's a bed in the back room,
but be warned that it's a bit dirty.
But that's your bed, right? I'd feel bad.
I am cursed, and do not sleep.
Pain, warmth...
I've forgotten many things.
Thank you, Doctor!
Doctor?
Yup! You helped me with my leg,
so I'll call you Doctor!
Okay?
Doctor, huh?
Sure. Call me whatever you please.
Let's go look for your house
once your leg has healed.
I will return by next dawn with food.
I'm sorry for only having berries today,
but please rest up for the time being.
Huh?
Are you going out?
Yes, by myself.
Really?
Don't worry. You will be safe here
so long as you don't go outside.
I won't go too far either.
Okay.
Then let me walk you to the door!
Oh!
I'm sorry.
N-No, my apologies.
Will you be heading to bed already?
Do you need my help?
Thanks, but I'll be fine by myself.
All right. Then I'll see you tomorrow.
I'll be okay...
Will I be able to wait until tomorrow?
M-Must hurry...
Tell everyone...
Everyone?
There's no point...
If all aren't...
Shiva?
Good morning.
Maybe she's still sleeping.
Where did she go?
Could she have gone out?
I see. She must have been frightened.
Of course she would run away.
Who wouldn't, when I look like this?
Saving that child in the first place was—
Shiva!
Oh, Doctor!
Shiva, where have you been?
I told you it was dangerous to go outside.
Ta-dah! For you!
What's this?
I was making a thank-you gift for you for yesterday!
Doctor, crouch down.
Thank you, but it's dangerous for you to touch me.
It's okay if I don't touch you, right?
Just crouch down.
But...
Stay still.
All right.
Be very careful.
Sure!
Yup, it looks great on you!
Thank you, Shiva.
Let's start with cleaning.
Okay!
I will handle the heavy lifting, so please
dust everything off and clean up the rubbish.
All right.
Shiva, once you're done over there,
could you clean this shelf, too?
Sure!
Shiva, I'll carry these items to my room,
so please leave them as they are.
Do you need any help?
Thank you kindly, but I'll be fine.
Oh, these as well.
They may get mixed up,
so I'll carry them my—
...and I thought it was a giant strawberry!
It must've been particularly large.
Good. Now wrap it up and we're done.
Okay! Thank you, Doctor!
All right!
Oh.
Thank you.
Doctor, there's some food I wanna try!
It's really fluffy and sweet,
and it has lots of sugar...
My apologies. It proved quite a feat.
Oh no, I'm sorry.
I've just never seen a pancake that was this burned!
Please eat only what looks edible.
I'm sure the burnt parts are tasty too.
They aren't good for you.
Then I'll just eat a little.
Is that a new curtain?
Yes. I found one that fits the frame just right.
All right, this should be good.
Shiva, it's ready!
Coming!
I'll be fine! I've had it many times before!
But with sugar, correct?
Yeah, but I feel like I can drink it today!
Careful not to burn yourself.
Okay!
Are you okay?
It's too bitter.
Doctor, did you find the sugar?
No, but I think there's some here.
Doctor!
There's a lotta books here!
That's very nice.
See if you can find anything you like.
Okay!
I found the sugar.
Huh? Really?!
Wait, I'll be right there!
See?
Can I have one?
Sure.
Sweet!
Doctor, let's play hide-and-seek!
Hide-and-seek?
Yeah!
Do I just count to ten?
Wait one second.
Umm...
Actually, a hundred!
A hundred then. All right.
Yeah!
One.
Two.
Three.
Four.
Five.
Six.
Seven.
Eight.
Nine.
Ten.
Eleven.
Twelve.
Thirteen.
Fourteen.
Hmm?
Could that be...
In a place like this?
Now is my chance...
l wonder where Doctor is.
Huh?
Hello! Are you playing hide-and-seek, too?
Oh, wait!
Aww...
What are you doing here?
You're not going to take it back?
Take what back?
Are you going to keep that soul all to yourself?
Soul?
Please elaborate.
You must hurry and return that soul
to Mother while it's still pure.
Mother?
What are you talking about?
This is about the soul that's with you.
What are you trying to do to Shiva?!
Shiva?
So you name your souls?
What do you mean?
You don't know?
All of us do.
Explain yourself.
That thing you call the curse...
Don't tell me...
You know how to break the curse?
Break the curse?
You truly are out of touch, aren't you?
Of course I am! I refuse to
spread the curse unlike you people!
Whose child are you?
"Whose child"?
l am human!
Then tell me your name.
What?
All humans have a name, do they not?
l am...
Are you really from the Inside?
You're not one of us, a dark child?
Silence! Leave this place at once!
Which are you?
l am...
Shiva?
You found me.
I apologise for taking my time.
Was I that good at hiding?
It would appear so.
Did you find your book?
No, not yet.
How about this one?
I choose this one!
I must at least protect her...
I will not allow her to be cursed.
So long as we can avoid that,
I'm sure that one day...
"The god who was punished"
"had everything taken away"
"and was turned into a hideous creature."
Shall we continue the rest next time?
Shiva?
Yeah...
Is it this?
Oh.
No! It matters a lot to you, right?
It's all right.
Can I open it?
Sure, go ahead.
Um...
Are these your friends?
My family.
I was once human.
Doctor, how did you become an Outsider?
Why isn't everyone else with you?
You don't want to tell me?
No,
I simply don't know.
I was a human who lived in the Inside,
and I had a wife and child.
I should have been living an ordinary life.
But I remember neither my voice nor appearance.
Or even my name or face.
I can't even tell for sure whether it was all real.
I see.
I wanted to keep any connection I had,
so I've kept it with me all this time.
But maybe I don't need it anymore.
That's not true!
It's okay if you can't remember.
Even if things have changed,
please stay beside them, Doctor.
I think that matters more than remembering.
Will I be able to, though?
Why do you ask?
Because...
I've been cursed.
Um, I...
Just when you...
Oh.
I'm sorry. What were you saying?
Never mind.
Nothing.
I see.
I've talked a little too much.
We've been on our feet all day,
so you must be tired.
Sleep well.
Thank you. Good night, Doctor.
Good night.
Stop...
No!
Why? Please, no...
Somebody, please...
Please come...
Somebody...
Thank you!
The pancake is nicely baked and tasty today!
Is it? I'm glad you like it.
Doctor, could you pass the sugar?
Sure.
Doctor?
Doctor!
The sugar...
Oh, my apologies.
Thank you.
Shiva, would you like to go somewhere far away?
Somewhere far away? Where?
Well, I don't have a destination in mind, but...
Okay! That sounds really fun!
Let's go after I eat this! I'm almost done!
No, it may take a couple of days,
so let's make sure we're well prepared
and head out tomorrow morning.
Could you help pack up everything we need?
Okay!
I believe it's around here.
Okay.
Doctor?
Shiva?
Is something wrong?
Can't sleep?
Umm...
Um, Doctor?
Hm?
Um...
I'm...
Ugh...
Geez!
We'll have to clean this up before we go!
Sorry for the trouble.
I appreciate your help.
You're welcome.
Good night, Doctor.
Good night, Shiva.
If we can find a small village
where humans are settled...
I'm sure that would be best for her.
Oh!
Shiva, are you ready?
Give me a minute! I'll be right there!
Shiva?
Coming!
This should be much safer for her
than if she were to stay with me.
If I can find a village with people,
I'm sure a kind soul will take care of Shiva.
I'm afraid this is the best option I have.
Beyond this place...
If there's a child close her age,
I'm sure she won't grow bored either.
She'll have much better food, too.
For Shiva, I must...
I must save her.
And I must do so while I still can.
That is the least I could do.
I'm home.
Something seemed different.
It's starting to spill out.
It's nearly empty.
Not that.
It didn't know about Mother.
Nothing at all.
No, it knows.
It's nearly empty.
You're concerned about that one.
Yes, that one will end its duty soon.
We won't be able to return it to Mother like that.
Let's just return the shell.
Is this it?
I was expecting it to be a longer walk.
Let's look around first.
Looks like this is a farm.
They even left their tools.
Here would be...
Oh, Shiva! Don't run off too far!
I didn't realize how much I was pushing her.
Pretty!
Huh?
Doctor, come over here!
There's a lotta rare flowers!
Shiva, I want to check the houses,
so could you wait for me here?
Aww, but I wanna look with you!
We can look for flowers once I'm back.
Okay!
Oh!
I see.
This village has already been...
Then we must visit the village further ahead.
Is that a villager?
No, it isn't one of them!
Shiva!
Must save...
Run! Hurry!
I must...
Shiva!
Save...
Are you all right, Shiva?
Doctor?
That was...
I see. They must all be the same.
This is where everyone went.
They didn't separate. They stayed together.
Shiva?
Doctor, lie down with me.
What's the matter?
Just lie down, please.
Doctor, please listen.
Before I met you, I woke up one time.
I was all alone and it was dark.
When I thought that I might not
be able to return to my village anymore,
I was so scared I couldn't move anymore.
I was scared, so I closed my eyes,
wishing someone would come.
And when I woke up again,
you were there, Doctor.
It's just as I thought.
Shiva, it may be difficult to return to your village,
but if we head for the Inside...
Shiva?
It's too late.
What are you saying? Don't tell me...
No, you're still okay!
No, Doctor, I'm...
Don't worry!
I'll do something about this!
No! Even before I met you, I already...
I'll get you through this!
You're still okay!
You'll be fine.
Are we spending the night here?
That would be best.
The sun has already set,
and it looks like it may rain.
Let's rest here.
If we dust it off, this place isn't too bad.
That's true.
Please don't put it out.
Good night.
Who is it at this hour?
Ah, I'm glad you noticed.
I was returning to the village up ahead,
but I came over after I saw your light.
Won't you leave this place behind
and come with me to the Inside?
Our village received permission from the king.
We appreciate your kindness, but we're fine.
Don't worry. No soldiers have come yet!
Why now of all times?
You can come with us as a villager.
Why right after I found out about her curse?
Or you can even stop by my house first.
If you're scared you're imposing on us, don't be!
We're fine! Just go!
I-Is that so? I get it.
I don't mean to overstep,
but my village is down the road to the west.
There's two houses lined up in the very back.
If only she weren't cursed...
My house is the one with a dog at the entrance.
We leave tomorrow at noon.
Don't hesitate to drop by
should you change your mind.
Is there nothing I can do?
ls she going to experience
the same loneliness by being cursed?
How cruel...
I lost even the faintest trace
of what I was looking for.
Life, time...
Everything had forsaken me.
She will also have to face this pain.
What is even left of me?
What could I...
What could I do for Shiva?
A soul...
If only I had a soul...
If I just attack him from behind...
There is no other choice. I must do this.
But would that be what she wished for?
What am I thinking? This is as if...
I must return.
Wha...
Drat!
You... monster!
Run! It's an Outsider! Run away!
Wait! Stop! Let go of me!
Stop! Don't touch me!
Run!
Stop!
Please, let go of me!
This fire should notify
the surrounding villages of you...
I don't attack villages...
We're finally...
We're finally able to move to the Inside.
So long as I don't spread the curse...
Stop! What are you...
Wait!
Stop! I haven't touched you yet...
No...
This can't be...
What...
What have I done?
Looks like you can no longer use that soul.
All I wanted was to help Shiva...
There's somewhere I want you to take me.
Yeah, sure.
Shiva, you brought this for me.
Here it is.
Stay with her for a moment.
We'll head further down.
Don't get lost.
This is it.
This is the closest.
We're home, Mother.
We don't have a soul, but we'll return this.
We have a guest today.
I can hear something.
It's Mother.
It's Mother's voice.
It's more like a sound than a voice.
Words don't do it justice.
It's more like a song.
Now, speak to Mother.
I would like to ask for a favour.
Please...
Save us.
Please tell me how to break her curse.
I'll do anything I can to help!
She is my light...
I was always in the dark.
If Shiva weren't there,
I would've been that way forever.
Forgetting my breath, my pulse,
my sleep, and even myself...
I don't want her to suffer the way I did!
To lose everything!
Please.
There's nothing more I can do for her.
I beg you. Please, save Shiva's soul.
If you can hear my voice,
please break this curse.
Shiva...
I...
There was nothing more I could do for you.
All I wanted...
was to stay with you.
Do you understand now?
It's just as Mother says.
You should have known what that meant for you.
I knew.
I knew there was an end to everything.
Shiva...
Can I not give?
Is taking from you all I can do?
No...
No! Doctor!
No!
Don't leave me!
Stay with me!
All right. I will.
If even someone like me
can become your light...
Doctor...
I think I was having a dream.
A really scary dream.
It was dark and quiet, and it felt like
I was going to be alone again...
Don't worry. I won't be leaving you.
Oh...
Sorry. I took it without asking.
Don't be. Thank you, Shiva.
Because of you, I decided
I should start taking better care of it.
Yeah!
Would you open it?
Shiva?
Doctor, I can walk.
Doctor.
Mhm?
Here you go.
Thank you, Shiva.
Doctor, sorry for making you wait!
Let's take the long way back.
Sure!